#大家好 今天去攝影小哥家摘點板粟哦
Hi everyone! Today we'll get some chestnuts from Mr. Cameraman's home.
#就在那邊
It's just over there.
#找們到了 你看這板粟
Here we are. See? The chestnuts.
#好大了哦
They're very big now.
#我去砍根竹子下來
I'll chop a bamboo,
#砍一根竹子下來 敲一下它 看能不能敲下來
chop a bamboo to knock the tree. See if I can knock off the chestnuts.
#把這個竹子打掉
Get rid of the branches
#然後用這個來打板粟
and then use it to knock the chestnuts.
#好啦
Enough!
#應該敲下十幾二十個下來
I should have more than a dozen now.
#不要啦 不要啦
Enough! Enough!
#下次我們帶一個籮筐 因為今天沒帶籮筐
We'll come again with a basket next time. We can't take too many today
#裝不了多少的
as we don't have a basket.
#把掍子放在這裡曬乾一點
I'll place the stick here to let it dry.
#太重啦 這根棍子
It's just too heavy!
#這裡有一個
There is one.
#先吃一下
Let me try,
#看好不好吃
and see if it tastes good.
#嗯 不錯哦
Um! Not bad!
#你看 這個攝影小哥奶奶種的攀蒲
See? The "panpu" (pumpkin) planted by Mr. Cameraman's grandma.
#最少四十斤以上
It's at least 20kg.
#下次我開個車過來 幫她拉回去
I'll come next time with my car to carry the pumpkin for her.
#攝影小哥肯定抱不動 我才抱得動
There is no way Mr. Cameraman can hold it. Only I can.
#來 給一個給你吃
Hey! This one is for you.
#這個還沒老哦 這個 還不到時間
This one is not mature enough, this one. Still not the time.
#我們就提前過來啦
We came too early.
#哇 這兩個
Wa! These two...
#很漂亮的哦
are so pretty!
#哇 裝不下啦 這兜滿啦 你看
Wa! I can't take anymore! The pockets are full. See?
#不要掉啦
Don't drop them.
#先把這個放到這裡 這裡
Put them here first, here.
#等下別掉啦
Don't drop them.
#裡面還那麼多 我看到
There are still so many inside, I can see.
#沒事
Never mind
#你個 這個拿藤果 下個月就快熟了哦
See? The wild melon. It will be ready next month.
#剛好攝影小哥身上有一支筆
It just so happens that Mr. Cameraman has a pen.
#我來寫一個
Let me write,
#我的名字上去
write my name on it.
#專
Exclusive
#專享 享受的受怎麼寫
Exclusive enjoyment. How do you spell "enjoyment"?
#教教我
Teach me!
#劉蘇良專享
"For the exclusive enjoyment of Liu Suliang"
#好啦 沒啦
Alright! No more!
#全部挖完啦
All are here.
#這個是攝影小 小哥家樹下敲下來的
These are from, from the trees of mister, Mr. Cameraman's home.
#還給他
He'll keep them.
#這個綠色的還給他 這個是我的 黑的
He'll have the green one. This is mine, this is black.
#黑的老的是我 是我憑本事撿的
I picked the black and old ones by, by my own effort.
#在隔壁家 隔壁兄弟家樹底下撿的 這個
They are picked under the tree of the neighbour, the brother next door.
#放到口袋裡面去先
Put them into the pockets.
#這還有一個壞的
There is one more rotten.
#沒壞
No, it's not rotten.
#攝影小哥喜歡吃嫩的
Mr. Cameraman likes younger ones.
#這些都是比較嫩的 給他吃
These younger ones are all for him.
#啊 這個就給你啦
Ah! Keep them.
#很嫩的哦
They are very young.
#哇 這板粟太多了啦
Wa! There are too many chestnuts.
#這會掉的
I'll drop them.
#誒 可以這樣子
Eh? How about...
#打個結 就沒那麼容易掉了
making a knot to secure it?
#來都來了
Well, I am already here.
#搞一個 搞一個攝影小哥家的攀蒲來吃一下 他家那麼多
Why not, why not take one Mr. Cameraman's "panpu"? He has so many!
#吃一完
He can't finish them.
#哇 挑一個小的嫩的來
Ah! Take this small and young one.
#哇 這一個比這一個還大哦
Wa! This one is even larger than this one!
#我要挑回去先
I'll get it.
#一個不好背 要兩個才好挑
It's difficult to take one on the back. Carrying two on a yoke is easier.
#搞個白 扁擔來
Get a faa...flat yoke first.
#看下去那麼大
It looks large only,
#砍下來那麼小
but it is not.
#這才叫 滿載而歸
This is called a "victory return",
#哦 哈哈哈哈哈
Ho ho ho, ha ha ha ha ha